MAX CHENG

www.linkedin.com/in/maxcheng98 | Fremont, CA | (408) 908-0395 | github.com/mbcheng88 | maxbcheng1688@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Skilled Accounting & Research Assistant with a master's degree in Biotechnology & Bioinformatics and growing experience in manipulating organisms to create new processes, diagnosing complex clinical diseases, studying characteristics of cells, conducting complex research, and developing new research procedures. Transferrable experience in managing cross-functional projects, analyzing large amounts of research, using data to make informed judgements, studying samples, and meeting reporting requirements. Continually exceeds expectations by building strong relationships and works well with people at all levels of the organization including senior management, staff, and clients.

Skills

- Analyzing Large Amounts of Research
- Manipulating Organisms to Create New Processes
- Using Data to Make Informed Judgements
- Diagnosing Complex Clinical Diseases
- Studying Characteristics of Cells
- Conducting Complex Research

- Developing New Research Procedures
- Collecting & Studying Samples
- Recording Findings & Analyzing Results
- Managing Cross-Functional Projects
- Meeting Reporting Requirements
- Excellent Verbal & Written Communication

Education

Johns Hopkins University 08/2020 to 05/2022

Master of Science, Biotechnology & Bioinformatics

- Utilized Python, Unix, SQL, and other bioinformatics tools on NGS workflows and designed FASTQ analysis websites.
- Integrated a variant calling pipeline to analyze novel SNP's for Parkinson's disease and outlined findings in an essay.
- Learned how to create vaccines to combat debilitating diseases and discover novel antibiotics from biological sources.
- Developed assays to diagnose complex clinical diseases and design drought/pesticide resistant crops for production.
- Obtained knowledge on how to use data to analyze samples to help solve clinical investigations.
- Studied the development and application of computational tools and techniques for the collection of biological systems.
- Prepared for bioinformatics, molecular biology, computational biology, systems biology, and medical informatics.
- Examined current societal issues in biotechnology from several perspectives and studied biohazards and bioethics.
- Explored business biotechnology, structure/operation, and the science upon which global industry sectors were founded.

University of California Davis

09/2016 to 06/2020

Bachelor of Science, Neurobiology, Physiology, and Behavior

Work History

Accounting Assistant - Action CPA Group, Inc - Milpitas, CA

10/2021 to Current

- Effectively answered client phone calls and scheduled appointments as well as entered data into the company database.
- Spearheaded the sorting/filing procedures for all important documents to ensure an organized and clean environment.
- Composed, prepared, edited, or distributed correspondence and other department documents to the relevant contacts.
- Expertly handled various office duties while multitasking and providing exceptional customer service simultaneously.
- Continuously provided administrative support, assisted with project development, and tracked all budgets and schedules.
- Strategically completed data entry, issued payroll checks, filed documentation, and managed cross-functional projects.

- Strategically tutored over 50 high school and college level students to exceed expectations and grade average goals.
- Employed various assessment tools and proactive strategies to improve instruction methods and foster creative thinking.
- Continuously created lesson plans according to student's academic needs, including both individual and group work.
- Accurately evaluated student progress to determine skill development and areas of opportunity for future study lessons.
- Developed rapport with students and established a fun learning environment to increase student knowledge retention.
- Successfully customized various tutoring and instructional approaches to meet the needs of diverse client populations.

Research Assistant – UC Davis MND Institute – Sacramento, CA

06/2017 to 09/2019

- Managed a team of 4 research assistants using Python scripts to convert ray fMRI data for data analysis.
- Communicated with the team regarding intermediate findings, challenges, and opportunities for further exploration.
- Analyzed, tracked, and reported data to make informed optimizations along with all research project recommendations.
- Influenced high prioritization of initiatives, aligning experiences across channels and touchpoints to ensure best results.
- Performed analyzation of asset classes and provided quantitative analysis of volumes of data to offer recommendations.
- Conferred with teams to resolve conflicts, prioritize needs, develop research criteria, and choose solutions for issues.

Technical Skills

Python (NumPy, Pandas, Matplot, Biopython) SQL, Git, Docker, Linux Command Line Competency, Microsoft Office Suite, Next Generation Sequencing Workflow Processing, Cromwell/WDL